DAVID BALDUS PAPERS (APAP329) 1965-2011
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
David Baldus Papers1965-20111965-2011
nam_apap329
The David C. Baldus Papers document the distinguished legal research career of David C. Baldus, which includes the most sophisticated challenges to capital punishment in the United States since the reinstatement of the Death Penalty in 1976. Included is material from the Georgia Charging & Sentencing Study, which was used as evidence in the McCleskey v. Kemp (1987) decision. Similar studies involving capital sentencing in New Jersey, Pennsylvania, and the U.S. Military are also detailed, as is Baldus's formal reports to the supreme courts of a number of other states. Also present is material documenting Baldus's long career as the Joseph B. Tye Professor of Law at the University of Iowa Law School. This includes teaching material, presentations, publications, and material documenting faculty service.
Baldus, David C.
192.3
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY
Acquisition Information
All items in the David C. Baldus Papers were acquired by the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, in 2011.
Biographical History
David C. Baldus was born in Wheeling, West Virginia in 1935 to Frank A. and Mary Baldus. He studied Government as an undergraduate at Dartmouth College, graduating in 1957, before serving with the Army Security Agency as a Lieutenant in Korea from 1958 to 1959. Baldus attended graduate school at the University of Pittsburgh where he was active in a number of political groups such as the Young Democrats and the Americans for Democratic Action. He obtained a Master of Arts in Political Science in 1962 and went on to study law at Yale University earning the LL.B. degree in 1964 (equivalent to a J.D.). He returned to practice law in Pittsburgh before obtaining his LL.M. degree from Yale in 1969. During this time Baldus was elected as the Democratic County Committeeman for the 4th District, 7th Ward in Pittsburgh in 1966, and also served on the Pennsylvania Constitutional Convention from 1967-1968. In 1969 he was appointed to the faculty at the University of Iowa College of Law, an affiliation that would last over 40 years. He was appointed full professor in 1972 and the Joseph B. Tye Professor of Law in 1983. Baldus also directed the Law and Social Sciences Program at the National Science Foundation from 1975-1976, and was the director of the Center for Interdisciplinary Legal Studies at the Syracuse University College of Law from 1981-1982.
Baldus taught at the University of Iowa College of Law for over 40 years, instructing students in Iowa Criminal Law, Federal Criminal Law, Admiralty Law, and Capital Punishment, as well as a theory course on abnormal criminal cases. He served a prominent role on the Faculty by participating in promotion and term reviews for professors both at Iowa and in the field of Criminal Law. Baldus also chaired the Academic Standards and Review Committee in the mid-2000s, which dealt with evaluations and issues of plagiarism.
In the early 1980s, Baldus began a study of the implementation of the death penalty in Georgia. The Georgia capital sentencing system had been declared arbitrary and unconstitutional by the Supreme Court in the Furman v. Georgia (1972) decision, causing a de facto nationwide moratorium on the death penalty. In the aftermath of the decision, Georgia and other states began implementing new sentencing measures in an attempt to impart objectivity and standardization. This included measures such as separate penalty trials, the codification of aggravating and mitigating factors, and the separation of murder into different degrees of severity. Four years after Furman, the Supreme Court upheld the new practices in three out of five states in a set of decisions headed by Gregg v. Georgia (1976) effectively defining a path where states could again legally sentence defendants to death. This new system was first challenged in Maxwell v. Bishop (1968) where a study performed by Marvin Wolfgang and Marc Riedel argued that the capital sentencing process was discriminatory towards African American defendants. During Maxwells appeal, future Supreme Court Justice Harry Blackmun rejected the Wolfgang study because it did not specifically examine the county where Maxwell was convicted, and because only controlled for 29 other variables, apart from race.
Decided in 1987, the Supreme Courts ruling in McCleskey v. Kemp became the most prominent challenge to capital punishment in the port-1976 era, and perhaps the most significant modern ruling on racial discrimination in the justice system. In a 5-4 split decision, the court ruled that, while Baldus's evidence showed significant racial discrimination in the capital punishment charging and sentencing system as a whole, the appeal failed to prove discrimination in the specific case of Warren McCleskey. The decision essentially barred the use of statistical evidence to prove unconstitutional discrimination in the justice system. Warren McCleskey was executed using the electric chair in 1991. After his retirement justice Lewis Powell, who authored the majority opinion, stated that the McCleskey ruling was the decision he most regretted.
After his prominent work on the Georgia capital system, Baldus's research turned to focus on discrepancies in Tort law, a field he would publish in during both the late-1980s and mid-1990s. Making use of this experience with social science research, he sought to develop the methodology and procedures used to conduct an empirical study on the review of awards made by juries in state courts for noneconomic damages. Notably, this came in the form of damages for medical malpractice. Baldus found these awards to be inconsistent and perhaps excessive. To establish more predicable awards, he developed systematic classification systems for Additur and Remittitur review of damages.
Baldus had gained substantial notoriety for is work in McCleskey. In the 1980s, the New Jersey Supreme Court requested a proportionality review of its capital sentencing system and appointed Baldus as Special Master to conduct the study. The case in question was the appeal of Robert O. Marshall who was convicted of hiring someone to kill his wife in 1984. Although the New Jersey court recognized statistical evidence of discrimination would pose a structural challenge to the state capital system, the New Jersey Proportionality Review failed to show evidence as strong as that which was presented in McCleskey. Baldus was not able to use logical regression because the regressions did not converge. Instead he relied on discriminate analysis, which, while finding significant race-of defendant effects, was more susceptible to methodological criticism. As a result,State v. Marshall was the first post-Furman capital appeal that was upheld by the New Jersey Supreme Court. The state later performed two more proportionality reviews performed by different Special Masters before becoming the first state to abolish the death penalty by legislation in 2007. Robert O. Marshalls sentence was reduced to live in prison in 2006. He spent a total of 30 years in prison before dying in 2015 at the age of 75.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of the legal research, teaching material, and professional communication of David C. Baldus, the Joseph B. Tye Professor of Law at the University of Iowa Law School. This includes the records of Baldus's extensive scholarly statistical research on the effects of race in the capital sentencing systems of many states. Also present are the records of Baldus's publications and his long career of teaching criminal law.
The collection includes correspondence, case files, data reports and statistical summaries, drafts of grant proposals and scholarly publications, notes used for writing and speaking, research and reference materials, and the records of and tools used for teaching. Most extensive are the case files used as part of Baldus's Pennsylvania research during the late 1990s and early 2000s. This material was gathered and stored by the Defenders Association of Philadelphia under David Zuckerman, who co-authored most of Baldus's publications on the state. Data reports and statistical summaries are also prevalent, and becomes even more common after Baldus began to make use of desktop statistical software after 2000.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into 19 topical series.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Subject and Genre Headings
Death Penalty; Baldus, David C.; Grosso, Cathi; McCleskey, Warren; Wilson, Harold C.; Woodworth, George; Zuckerman, David; Capital punishment--Illinois; Capital punishment--Law and legislation; Death penalty; Discrimination in capital punishment--United States; Legal research and writing; Legal research--Data processing; Legal research--Illinois; Administrative reports; Correspondence; Files by subject; Legal documents; Official reports; Questionnaires; Syllabi
Container List
- Calendars, Notebooks, and Desk Reference, 1994-2010; 1; 1.8
  The series is arranged chronologically.
  Includes David C. Baldus's daily desk calendars, general notebooks, and material that appears to have been kept on hand as desk reference.
  - Daily Desk Calendar, 1994 January-July (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Daily Desk Calendar, 1994 August-December (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Daily Desk Calendar, 1995 January-July (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Daily Desk Calendar, 1995 August-December (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Daily Desk Calendar, 1996 January-July (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Daily Desk Calendar, 1996 August-December (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Daily Desk Calendar, 1997 January-July (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Daily Desk Calendar, 1997 August-December (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Daily Desk Calendar, 1998 January-July (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Daily Desk Calendar, 1998 August-December (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Daily Desk Calendar, 2001 January-July (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Daily Desk Calendar, 2001 August-December (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Daily Desk Calendar, 2002 January-July (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Daily Desk Calendar, 2002 August-December (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Daily Desk Calendar, 2003 January-July (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Daily Desk Calendar, 2003 August-December (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Daily Desk Calendar, 2004 January-July (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Daily Desk Calendar, 2004 August-December (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Daily Desk Calendar, 2005 January-July (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Daily Desk Calendar, 2005 August-December (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Daily Desk Calendar, 2006 January-July (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Daily Desk Calendar, 2006 August-December (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Daily Desk Calendar, 2007 January-July (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Daily Desk Calendar, 2007 August-December (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Daily Desk Calendar, 2008 January-July (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Daily Desk Calendar, 2008 August-December (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Daily Desk Calendar, 2010 January-July (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Daily Desk Calendar, 2010 August-December (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Daily Desk Calendar, 2011 January-July (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Daily Desk Calendar, 2011 August-December (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Spiral Notebook, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Spiral Notebook-DB Computer, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Spiral Notebook, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Spiral Notebook, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Spiral Notebook-DB Phone log, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Spiral Notebook, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Spiral Notebook, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Spiral Notebook-Phone calls, 1997 September 22 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Spiral Notebook, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - International Association of Air Travel Couries, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - A Uniform System of Citation, Fourteenth Edition, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Business Card Stack, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Phone Numbers and Email Addresses, 1997; 2004; Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Phone Numbers and Email Addresses, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Spiral Notebook, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Contact Information, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Contact Information, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Contact Information-Research Assistants, Cathi Grosso, Jonathan Hendrix, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Mike Millemann Contact Information, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Jim Fyfe Contact Information, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Address File, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Calendar, 2009-2010 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Addresses, 2000; 2001; Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Faculty Papers, 1966-2011; 2; 7.6
  This series includes the records of David C. Baldus's service on the faculty at the University of Iowa School of Law. This consists of records of governance activities such as punitive issues and committees he served on. Scholarly material that did not fall under any other series scope is also featured here mainly represented as his research, correspondence, and notes that have a more general focus than any specific project. This also includes annotated published research materials.
  - Richard Lempert, "Strategies of Research Design in the Impact Study: The Control of Plausible Rival Hypotheses", 1966; 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Pennsylvania Constitutional Convention Directory of Delegates David C. Baldes member, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Contracts and L.S.P.", 1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Student paper- "Contracts and L.S.P., 1969; 1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Academic Standards and Review Committee- Old Promotion Tenure Standards, 1973; 1985; 2001 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Ben Credentials - Supreme Court of Pennsylvania, 1976 March (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - James S. Liebman, et. Al., " A Broken System: Error Rates in Capital Cases, 1973-1995; 2000 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Race and the Death Penalty in Kentucky Murder Trials: 1976 - 1991, A study of Racial Bias as a Factor in Capital Sentencing", 1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "A Guide for Selecting Statistical Techniques for Analyzing Social Science Data, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bar Credentials, 1979; 1980; 1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - David C. Baldus, et. Al., " Identifying Comparatively Excessive Sentences of Death: A Quantitive Approach, " Stanford Law Review vol. 33 no. 1, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Employment Contract, Joesph B. Tye Professorship and Research Funding, 1983; 1996 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Capital Sentencing Experiment, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Critics- Reviews of Equal Justice and the Death Penalty, 1986-1991 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Handout - "Usable Knowledge from the Social Sciences: A Lawyer's Perspective", 1987 April 10 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Critics- Joesph L. Katz, Atlanta Journal and Constitution Articles, 1987 August - September (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Crtics- Joesph L. Katz Iowa City Press Citizen Article, 1987 October (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Citations- n. 43, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Citations- n. 43, p. 790, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Citations - n. 62, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Citations - n. 64, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Citations - n. 73, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Citations - n. 82, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Citations - n. 88, p. 261-271, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Citations - n. 93, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Citations - n. 101, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Citations - n. 105, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Citations - n. 122 p. 28, 34, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Citations - n. 124, p. 290, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Citations - n. 124, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Citations - n. 128, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Citations - n. 129, p. 201, 206 -207, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Citations - n. 130, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Citations - n. 130, p. 480, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Citations - n. 133, p. 496, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Citations- n. 133, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Citations - n. 134, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Citations- n. 139, p. 314, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Citations - n. 192, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Citations, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Citations - n. 135, p. 261, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Citations - n. 136, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Citations- n. 138, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Citations- n. 144, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Citations- n. 145, 406 US 404 (1972), 1987 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Citations- n. 146, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Citations- n. 152, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Citations- n. 158, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Citations- n. 159, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Citations- n. 167, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Citations- n. 168, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Citations- n. 169, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Citations- n. 171, p. 118, 16-23, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Citations- n. 182, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Citations- n. 188, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Citations- n. 191, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Citations- n. 192, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Critics- Stephen Klein, with Correspondence with Michael Rudulet and Samuel R. Gross, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Data Reports- Unknown Study, 1989 May 23 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Faculty Activity Report, 1989-1990; 1993; 1996-1997; 2000 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Critics- General Accounting Office (GAO), 1990 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Critics- Stephen Klein, 1990; 1995 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Critics- William Edmundson, 1990; 1991 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Summer Research Awards, 1990; 1996; 1998 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Death Penalty Sentences in California, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Collection of Handwritten Speaking Notes in Binder- Discusses Proportionality Review, New Jersey, McCleskey v. Kemp Bill Boues Capital Jury Project, Quantum of Damages, 1992 April 23; 1993 January 27; Undated (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Tenure/ Promotion Review- Casel, 1992; 2007 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Association of American Law Schools (AALS) Workshop on Criminal Law, 1993 October 28-30 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Ken Kress, " Coherence and Formalism", 1993 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Research Assistant Work, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Samuel R. Gross, "The Romance of Revenge: Capital Punishment in Ameirca, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - University of Iowa Operations Manual, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Draft- " Discrimintaion and Models of Proof in Mortgage Lending: A Legal Perspective", 1994 Janurary 14 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Association of American Law Schools (AALS), 1994 June - July (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Critics- Ed Koch, 1994 November - 1995 January (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Science Editorial, " Scientific Evidence in Court", 1994 December (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Critics- Joesph L. Katz, Stephen Markman, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Faculty Development Award, 1994; 1995 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - New York Times Series on the Death Penalty, 1995 February (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Bar Credentials, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - McClesky v. Kemp with annotations, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Law School Floor Plan and Space Inventory, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Crtics- John E. Rolph, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Michael J Brody Award, 1996; 1997 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Faculty Development Awards, 1996; 2000; 2002; 2005 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Faculty Development Awards, 1996; 2000; 2002 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Critics Richard Cohen, 1997 January; 1997 February; 1997 May (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - The Geraldo Rivera Show Transcript, 1997 April 3 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - New York Times Article Sent to Noel Cohen, 1997 April 18 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Critics- Joesph L. Katz Bibliography, 1997 December; Undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Bar Credentials- Iowa Supreme Court, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - External Lectures- Mark Galanter, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Letters of Recommendation, References, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence- Michael P. Judge, Los Angeles County Public Defender, 1998 June 1 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Michael Radelet Florida Mitigation Study- Case List, 1998 June 15 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Extenal Faculty Review- Stephen P. Garvey, 1998 November 8 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Job Talk- Rent to Own Furniture and Welfare Reform, ca. 1998 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - McClesky v. Kemp with annotations, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Nicholas Johnson, " So You Want to be a Lawyer: A play in Four Acts", 1998 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Sheila Foster, "Intent and Incoherence," on discriminatory intent standard with notes, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - External Faculty Review- Craig J. Albert, Deterrence Article Critique, 1999 November (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - David Weisburd, Presentation: " Good for What Purpose?: Social Science, Race and Proportionality Review in New Jersey", 1999 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Article Manuscript Review- Hashem Dezhbakhsh, Paul H. Rubin, et. Al., "Does Capital Punishment Have a Deterrent Effect? New Evidence from Post- moratorium Panel Data (Emory Study) [with Floppy Disk], 1999 June; 2001 January (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Iowa Research Council, 2000 April 13 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - AAUP- Non-Tenure Research Track, 2000 May 3 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - New Jersey Proportionality Review Project- David S. Baime, 2000 August 8 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence- John C. Reitz paper on study of comparative public law, 2000 October 9 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - American Bar Association (ABA) " Call to Action: A Moratorium on Executions", 2000 October 12 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Reference for Clerkship [with 3.5 in. Floppy disk], 2000 November (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Academic Standards and Review Committee- Unfittness, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Barry Latzer and James N.G. Cauthen article and James S. Liebman, Jefferey Fagan and Valerie West response- Nebraska DCE and Mitigation Detailed, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Board of Regents Award for Faculty Excellence, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - David C. Baldus Citations since 2000, 2007 November (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Research Track Positions, 2000; 2002 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - University of Iowa Operations Manual, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence- Federal Death Penalty Study, D.C. Meeting, 2001 January-Februrary (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence- Career Develpoment Award, 2001 March 13 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Police Study- "Legal and Methodological Issues Concerning Police Stops of Automobiles and Pedestrians and Police Use of Force", 2001 March 13 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Deterrance Aricle Critiques- Emory Study and Dale O. Cloninger, et. Al, "Execution and Deterrence: Contolled Group Experiment", 2001 April; 2001 October; 2002 June (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Computer Hard Disk Drive Directory Print Out, 2001 July (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Michael Radelet Florida Mitigation Study- Case List, 2001 August 15 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence- William B. Fairley, 2001 October 3 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Billings- Commercial Storage, 2001 October (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Deterrance Aricle Critiques- Naci H. Mocan and R. Kaj Gittings," Pardons, Eexcutions and Homicide", 2001 December; 2002 January (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Cirrculum Vitae, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Summer Research Awards, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Law Review Death Penalty Articles, ca. 2001 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Research, articles, and notes on Proportionality Review, 2001-2003 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Student Evaluations- Professor William G. Buss, Hard Cases, 2001-2004 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - New York State Study of Capital Case Charging, Advancement and Sentencing- DCI Draft, 2002 January (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - New York State Study of Capital Case Charging, Advancement and Sentencing- DCI Draft, 2002 January (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - New York State Study of Capital Case Charging, Advancement and Sentencing- Research Design Draft, 2002 January (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Billings- San Francisco Charter Boat Rental, 2002 March 13 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Deterrance Article Critique- James Liebman Correspondence, 2002 March (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Literature- New York Death Penalty Law, 2002 March (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Literature- New York Death Penalty Law, 2002 March (Box 3, Folder 18)